Tyrone Showers

Seattle, WA 98106

(425) 381-9986 • booker.showers@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/bookershowers/

Senior Software Engineering & Development Executive

A distinguished and versatile leader in IT/SaaS project management and business development with over 20 years of groundbreaking experience. Drives dynamic companies and their clients to success with web design, cloud architecture, digital transformation, and CI/CD. As a results-focused leader, directs and inspires teams to perform and deliver at their best.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Project Management • Strategic Planning & Growth • IT Operations • Thought Leadership • SLA Negotiation • SaaS eCommerce • DevOps • Cloud Migration • AI/ML • API/REST • UX Architecture • Cross-Functional Collaboration CI/CD • Design Strategy & Road Mapping • Communication • Attention to Detail • Ad Hoc Reporting • Curiosity

EXPERIENCE

US BIOTEK LABORATORIES | Shoreline, WA

1/2021-7/2022

Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments (CLIA) accredited testing facility providing immunology and chemistry profiles to clinicians worldwide with focus on food safety and Covid testing.

Director of Technology, Cloud, and IT Infrastructure

- Hired into senior role to direct and architect direct to consumer websites in full collaboration with CEO, CFO, and
 marketing team. Help to strategize and plan out next steps.
- Negotiate and certify service level agreements with end users of systems.
- Support ad hoc reporting and date dependent projects to rigorous standards of quality.
- Perform hands-on development with Cloud Functions, Angular, Nodejs APIs, CI/CD pipeline implementation.

Select Achievements

- Independently launched LIS and six different eCommerce websites, including Notch B2C, an eCommerce lab test ordering website for signature spin off company, enabling consumers to order food sensitivity and covid testing without a doctor.
 - Completed previously stalled project within three months of hire.
 - Led to \$100K in monthly sales generation.

PK GLOBAL | Bellevue, WA

1/2020-1/2021

Regional consulting company focused on recruitment process outsourcing (RPO) and staff augmentation.

Chief Architect

Hired to develop roadmap, guiding company to achieve 2020 architectural objectives for key client, T-Mobile.

- Evaluated security readiness of APIs with particular attention to massive data access project for T-Mobile.
 - o Defined and assembled 88 guiding principles of API and served as SME on API security.
- Mentored, recruited, and assessed performance of 75 architects, developers, testers, and analysts.

WIPRO LIMITED | Bellevue, WA

8/2018-6/2020

Key SaaS vendor/supplier to T-Mobile and $AT \mathcal{C}T$.

Enterprise and API Architect

- Led E2E planning, architecture, testing, and deployment for range of B2B clients with particular focus on ongoing service contracts with AT&T for Azure cloud asset/inventory management system.
- Performed direct sales and client negotiations on scope of projects and deliverables.
- Recruited, vetted, and hired 20 new team members.

Select Projects & Achievements

- Won company's coveted Excellent Contribution Award for service and performance in mobile API, Cloud and REST initiatives on the T-Mobile platform.
- Designed, architected, and managed proposal for \$7M web portal for National General Insurance Corporation (NGIC).
- Delivered complete infrastructure to unify pharma company Takeda's finance systems across all constituent platforms. Completed full \$2M Sun Solaris to Linux migration for S&P Global.

Specialized IT consultancy partnered with WIPRO to target SaaS solutions; AT&T preferred vendor.

Principal Consultant, Independent Consultant, Business Developer, E-Commerce, REST & Cloud SME

- Served as project lead to provide thought leadership and alternative solutions for Cloud, API, REST, DevOps, and eCommerce solutions for clients in close collaboration with senior executive team.
- Integral member of API Privacy, Legal and Security Approval Committee; responsible for provision of direction to clientele on correct Error Handling, API Policy, and API versioning techniques.
- Orchestrated continuous improvement plan to ensure end to end traceability of scripts, code, configurations, and design.
- Helmed REST and DevOps best practice initiatives; navigated REST design and architectural requirements.

Select Projects and Achievements

- Architected and coordinated with specialized technology professionals at key client AT&T to design Customer Landing Page, Identification, Mobile Identity, Fraud Identity, and Offers.
 - Introduced E-commerce taxonomy, road map and architecture which immediately resulted in faster functional deployment and improved productivity and efficiency metrics by ~60%.
 - Oversaw approval, design, and consultation on WebRTC, SMS, In-App Messaging, Advertising, Push-to-Talk, Digital Live, U-verse and M2X.
 - Led to being recognized and designated as AT&T's chief REST and AWS SME for 2011-2016.
- Created and implemented product development roadmap to maximize resources, resulting in a 25% decrease in software development expenses.
- Designed, implemented, and directed deployment of fast-food SaaS for Popeye's Chicken that implemented complete accounting and administration system
 - Resulted in 75% IT budget reduction, and successfully reduced accounts receivables outstanding payments by 35%, with dramatically increased efficiency overall.
- Won 2011 Excellent Contribution Award for service and performance in mobile API, Cloud and REST initiatives leading to vastly expanded footprint with AT&T.

ACCENTURE | Miami, FL

10/2006-8/2009

Leading professional services and IT management consulting firm.

Information Technology, eCommerce, and Project Manager

• Led and directed multiple SOA, SaaS, SDP, and E-Commerce projects; served as member of Executive SaaS workgroup and SME for elite SaaS Steering Committee.

CARMEL MANAGEMENT | Miami, FL

7/2005-10/2006

Online pharmaceutical company.

Vice President of Information Technology

- Promoted from external Consultant to VP of Information Technology driving \$1M revenue a day for eCommerce pharmacy; achieved 12% additional revenue through vendor collaboration in prescription reaction information.
- Oversaw IT annual budget and IT personnel including Operations, Directors, Managers, Analysts, Testers, and Network Administrators, encompassing all aspects of staffing, training, performance management, and compensation

LIFERRO | Miami, FL

5/2001-7/2005

Self-started SaaS provider.

Chief Technology Officer & Co-Founder

- Pioneered, architected, and developed industry-first integrated SaaS product line validating web-based applications for clients including the NFL Players Association.
- Featured in Miami Herald as CEO of one of first SaaS companies.

ECHOBRIDGE | Miami, FL

11/2000-5/2001

IT solutions developer.

Chief Framework Architect

• Managed overall responsibility for architecture; directed IT personnel including developers, network administrators, and analysts. Architected and designed framework for high-profile Johnson and Johnson Gateway presence.

EDUCATION

DEVRY UNIVERSITY | Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

CERTIFICATIONS

• Certified in Microsoft Active Directory, 2020

TECHNICAL

- Methodologies: Lean, Scrum, Waterfall, Agile, Extreme Programming (XP), RUP, SOA, DevOps, Serverless.
- Languages: CSS, Java, JavaScript (JSON), SQL, XML, C++, Assembler, TypeScript.
- Operating Systems/Frameworks: TPF, .NET, SDP, Apache (Tomcat, Cassandra, Subversion), WebSphere, Microsoft Commerce Server, MySQL, Angular, node.js, Git, CVS, Docker, Kubernetes,.
- Security Architecture: SDP, Passwordless Authentication, Managed Security Services, Firewall Management, DDOS.
- Cloud: AWS, Azure, Google Cloud and Firebase,
- API/API Management: APIGEE, REST, Swagger, Twilio, Stripe, Acuity, Shopify, Sendgrid, AT&T.
- Software: Microsoft Project, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook) Eclipse, Lawson, iWork, MATLAB.

PUBLIC SPEAKING

• Apex Systems, 2022 - conducted well-regarded talk as SME on cloud architecture and other digital topics for up-and-coming IT professionals.